LUCCA WANG | SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Las Cruces, NM, 88012 | luccawang@gmail.com | 415-763-7534

LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

Full-stack software engineer, developing with Python, Flask, Postgres/databases, SQL on backend; JavaScript, React, HTML, and CSS for data flow and visually on the DOM on the frontend. Works with APIs and the CS fundamentals and industry tools, including Code, Git, CL, GitHub, and more. Mature creative thinker, problem solver, and communicator with previous professional work experience.

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages | Python, JavaScript (AJAX, JSON), CSS, HTML

Frameworks & Libraries | React, Flask, Agile

Industry Tools | Git, GitHub, GitLab, Jinja2, Pair Programming, SQL, SQLAlchemy, Testing, VSCode

Databases | PostgreSQL, ActionKit, Osnium, NGP, Datatel, Salesforce

General/Software | Email on Acid, WordPress, Drupal, MailChimp

PROJECTS

PetPlanner | GitHub | Demo | (Python, Flask, JavaScript, React, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, APIs)

- Full-stack web app built from scratch used by pet owners to centralize their pets' information in one location.
- Created an extensive and foundational data model and PostgreSQL database for many- and one-to-many relationships.
- Overcame date and time challenges, including in the data flow between the Python backend and the JS and React frontend.
- Integrated three APIs, and utilized conditional and dynamic rendering (including with Python's Jinja2 and React.js' mapping)

Let's Eat! | GitHub | (Python, Flask, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, API)

- Full-stack web app built from scratch, providing a solution to psychological analysis paralysis and simplifying decision making.
- Acquired and applied expertise in website accessibility standards and best practices.
- Leveraged Python's Random module and logic for the backend.
- Utilized media queries to create a responsive web app adaptable to multiple screen sizes.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Tech and Web Engineer Volunteer

July - Present 2024

Las Cruces Tennis Player Association, Southwest Region, USTA, Las Cruces, NM

• Assess, evaluate, advise, and recommend technologies and for company needs.

Student Full-stack Software Engineer

Hackbright Academy, 100% Remote, San Francisco, CA

Nov. 2023 – Feb. 2024

- Full-time 12-week immersion in core programming; CS data structures; Python OOP; JavaScript and React; Postgres relational databases and SQL; data modeling; unit and integration testing; and web technologies HTML, CSS, Flask, and APIs.
- Participated in daily scrum stand up meetings and collaborated with at least one cohort colleague per day during lab work.
- Built a solo independent fullstack web app, and earned scores of 91-99% on all (7) technical assessments throughout the program.

Digital and Content Strategist

Feb. 2022 - Aug. 2023

GPS Impact, 100% Remote, Des Moines, IA

- Coded and sent 5-9 political fundraising emails a day with a text editor, HTML, AWS S3, and a SQL database mail client.
- Created weekly and quarterly documentation to report performance (in-depth metrics on donations, email, social).
- Debugged and conducted manual and A/B testing within Theory of Change; collaborated with department tech lead.
- Hired and mentored 2 paid interns who worked 30 hours a week and contributed to client work weekly.

Freelance Communications and Marketing Consultant

March 2020 - Jan. 2023

Self, 100% Remote, Las Cruces, NM

- Identified objectives with client teams and leveraged project management skills to increase following, visibility, credibility, and sales.
- Produced communications deliverables, established processes, and coached client teams on best practices.

Communications Coordinator

June 2017 - Dec. 2020

Kansas Coalition Against Sexual and Domestic Violence, Topeka, KS

- Worked with IT, website and database engineers, and project managers on products and services to meet business needs.
- Created a manual for documentation on the website; trained staff on the new website, which I developed with directors.
- Planned events and budgeting plus fundraising; oversaw volunteers.
- Wrote, produced, and oversaw website, social, email, media relations, newsletter, executive speeches, and various reports.

EDUCATION

Hackbright Academy, Accelerated 12-week Fellowship; Certificate in Software Engineering

Nov. 2023 - Feb. 2024 Aug. 2011 - Sept. 2012

San Francisco Art Institute, Bachelor of Fine Arts, Studio Art

Drake University, Bachelor of Arts, Journalism and Mass Commu

Aug. 2007 - May 2011

Drake University, Bachelor of Arts, Journalism and Mass Communication; Bachelor of Arts, Arts & Sciences

ACTIVITIES & AWARDS

- Awarded O'Reilly 2024 Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Justice Scholarship
- Attended WomenHack San Diego April 30, 2024 (Virtual) event
- Attended DeveloperWeek 2024

June 2023 – June 2024

April 30, 2024

February 28-29, 2024